<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-02-15T23:34:56-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Sean Chen</title><subtitle>A personal blog to share about technology, food, travel, etc.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Asia Trip 2017</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/2018/02/15/asia-trip.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Asia Trip 2017" /><published>2018-02-15T10:46:21-08:00</published><updated>2018-02-15T10:46:21-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/2018/02/15/asia-trip</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/2018/02/15/asia-trip.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve never been the strongest writer, so I decided to give myself an easy topic to write about for my first blog post (that isn’t the intro post). This post will be about a two week trip I took in the spring of 2017 with my brother Kevin and my friend Tony through Southeast Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, some background on my motivation for taking the trip. When I graduated from Cal at the end of 2015, I knew that I wanted to do some traveling before I started working. I took a three week trip through four different countries in Europe and one in Africa (a story for another time) and loved backpacking so much that I promised myself that I would take some time each year to explore a new part of the world that I had never been before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I don’t mind traveling alone (it’s great way to force yourself to meet new people), I knew that I wanted to travel with Kevin at some point. I floated the idea of Southeast Asia to him and he said that both him and his roommate Tony had been wanting to go, so they were completely on board. At this point, Kevin was still living in Arlington, VA with Tony so we needed to plan out the logistics of the trip. I knew from my previous trip that my preferred method of planning trips was to pick the cities and the dates, get the flights for those cities, and then leave the nitty-gritty details of each city for when I got there. If there was something that I definitely wanted to do in a specific city, then I would book something in advance, but I liked the freedom of choosing what I would be doing, the day of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some discussion, this was our finalized itinerary:
&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/asia-trip/trip-itinerary.jpg&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;
We were going to fly into Singapore and stay for one day. Then fly to Thailand, jumping between Phuket, Chiang Mai, and Bangkok. Finally, we would go to three more cities in Vietnam - Hanoi, Nha Trang, and Ho Chi Minh City. We wanted to see as many places as we could, so we were only spending 2 or 3 days max in each city. Some of the things we knew we wanted to do were a Thai cooking class, and a boat cruise in Ha Long Bay (near Hanoi) so we booked those in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the three of us in SF the day before we set off for the trip:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/asia-trip/start-sf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be continued…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I’ve never been the strongest writer, so I decided to give myself an easy topic to write about for my first blog post (that isn’t the intro post). This post will be about a two week trip I took in the spring of 2017 with my brother Kevin and my friend Tony through Southeast Asia.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First blog post!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/informational/2018/02/13/first-blog-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First blog post!" /><published>2018-02-13T13:53:48-08:00</published><updated>2018-02-13T13:53:48-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/informational/2018/02/13/first-blog-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/informational/2018/02/13/first-blog-post.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been wanting to start a blog for a while now, but have never gotten around to it. So I decided to stop being lazy and start today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is going to be a combination of posts about tech that I’m currently learning about, recipes that I’ve attempted (with pictures :D), places that I’ve recently visited, as well as anything else that is occupying my time. My goal is to write one blog post every two weeks. Hopefully, I’m not all over the place with these blog posts and can both learn and teach through them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. I will be sharing some of my photography through the background images of this blog. (Plaza Major in Madrid above)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I’ve been wanting to start a blog for a while now, but have never gotten around to it. So I decided to stop being lazy and start today.</summary></entry></feed>